<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>openssl on My Hugo</title>
    <link>/tags/openssl/</link>
    <description>Recent content in openssl on My Hugo</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 17 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/tags/openssl/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>A 6 Part Introductory OpenSSL Tutorial</title>
      <link>/core/security/openssl-tutorial/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/core/security/openssl-tutorial/</guid>
      <description>OpenSSL is among the most popular cryptography libraries. It is most commonly used to implement the Secure Sockets Layer and Transport Layer Security (SSL and TLS) protocols to ensure secure communications between computers. In recent years, SSL has become basically obsolete since TLS offers a higher level of security, but some people have gotten into the habit of referring to both protocols as “SSL.”
Cryptography is tricky business, and OpenSSL has too many features to cover in one article, but this OpenSSL tutorial will help you get started creating keys and certificates.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OpenSSL Cookbook</title>
      <link>/core/security/openssl-cookbook/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/core/security/openssl-cookbook/</guid>
      <description>1 OpenSSL OpenSSL is an open source project that consists of a cryptographic library and an SSL/TLS toolkit. From the project’s web site:
The OpenSSL Project is a collaborative effort to develop a robust, commercial-grade, full-featured, and Open Source toolkit implementing the Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) and Transport Layer Security (TLS) protocols as well as a full-strength general purpose cryptography library. The project is managed by a worldwide community of volunteers that use the Internet to communicate, plan, and develop the OpenSSL toolkit and its related documentation.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OpenSSL Essentials: Working with SSL Certificates, Private Keys and CSRs</title>
      <link>/core/security/openssl-cert-key-csr/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/core/security/openssl-cert-key-csr/</guid>
      <description>source
Introduction OpenSSL is a versatile command line tool that can be used for a large variety of tasks related to Public Key Infrastructure (PKI) and HTTPS (HTTP over TLS). This cheat sheet style guide provides a quick reference to OpenSSL commands that are useful in common, everyday scenarios. This includes OpenSSL examples of generating private keys, certificate signing requests, and certificate format conversion. It does not cover all of the uses of OpenSSL.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
