<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>postgres on My Hugo</title>
    <link>/core/db/postgres/</link>
    <description>Recent content in postgres on My Hugo</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="/core/db/postgres/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>launch-by-docker</title>
      <link>/core/db/postgres/launch-by-docker/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/core/db/postgres/launch-by-docker/</guid>
      <description>The quickest setup is using docker.
The Server get postgres docker image docker pull postgres docker image ls postgres REPOSITORY TAG IMAGE ID CREATED SIZE postgres latest f51c55ac75ed 2 weeks ago 314MB prepare a folder that contains pg data and a file that contains environment variables to avoid expose them on command-line a folder on the host that actually contains database data mkdir -p /c/opt/pg/data cat &amp;gt; /c/opt/pg/svr.env POSTGRES_PASSWORD=super-acc-postgres-passwd ^D create a shell script to launch server docker run -d --name dev-pg --env-file /c/opt/pg/svr.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>postgresql user</title>
      <link>/core/db/postgres/user/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/core/db/postgres/user/</guid>
      <description>hints after installed, you can access the server using postgres account as superuser from localhost login as postgres or use -U postgres (as root) from localhost, no password is required there&amp;rsquo;s no default password jdbc connection string jdbc:postgresql:&amp;lt;host[:port]&amp;gt;/&amp;lt;database&amp;gt;?user=&amp;lt;USER&amp;gt;&amp;amp;password=&amp;lt;PASSWD&amp;gt; non-alphabet character should be url-encoded, such as - to %2D create a user login as postgres run command createuser name TBC create role psql -U postgres postgres=# create database mydb; \connect mydb create table boys (id integer, name varchar(32)); create role ddp; alter role ddp with password &amp;#39;ddp-pwd&amp;#39;; grant all on database mydb to ddp; grant all on table boys to ddp; psql -U ddp -h localhost -d mydb mydb=&amp;gt; select * from boys; </description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
